Hello, today in this video I will
compare two health insurance plans
which are Niva Bupa Aspire and
ICICI Lord Max Protect Plan.
At the end of the video we will talk about bonus tip and the
premium and terms of this plan.
One important thing before starting the video is
if you haven't subscribed to our channel yet then
subscribe so that
you get the right information at the right time.
Now I would like to introduce myself.
My name is Kajal. I keep giving you
updates related to health and life insurance
through this channel and
also give you advice on every insurance related problem. Our team has
12 years of experience in the insurance industry
and we also provide consultancy related to claims.
Let's start today
's video. Before starting the video, we will
look at the claim settlement ratio of Niva B Health Insurance Company and ICICI Lord. The
claim settlement ratio of ICICI Lombard Health Insurance Company is 91.6.7 and the
claim settlement ratio of ICICI Lombard
is 91.6. Data on 88.5% S 2021 & 22
First of all, we will know
about the sum insured options available in these plans. In Tova B
Aspire Plan, you get sum insured options ranging from ₹ lakh to ₹
crore.
This plan is available in four variants -
Gold Plus, Diamond Plus,
Platinum Plus, and Titanium Plus.
In ICICI Labad Max Protect Plan, you can choose between ₹ 50 lakh, ₹ 1 crore, ₹ 3 crore, ₹ 5 crore, ₹ 10
crore, and unlimited options. By
choosing the unlimited option,
you can claim as much as you want.
In ICICI Labad Max Protect Plan, you get two variants which are
Classic and Premium.
Worldwide coverage is available in the premium variant. Now let's
talk about the minimum and
maximum entry age of these plans. In Tova B
Aspire Plan and ICICI Labad Max
Protect Plan, the minimum
entry age for an adult is 18 years, and the maximum entry age is 18 years for
both.  The age limit for the plans is 65 years.
Talking about the child age coverage in these plans, the
minimum entry age is 91 days in the De Va Bupa Aspire and ICICI Lombard Max Protect plans
and the maximum child
entry age is 30 years in the Niva Bupa Spire plan. The
best thing here is that you
can keep the child with you even after 30 years in the Niva Bupa Spire plan and the maximum
age of children in the ICICI Lombard Max Protect plan is 25 years.
In the ICICI Lombard Max Protect plan, the minimum age for an individual policy is
6 years. In both the plans, you
can renew the policy for life time.
Now let's know about the cover type.
Individual and family floater plans
are available in both the Niva Bupa Aspire plan and ICICI Lombard Max Protect plan. Now, if we talk about the policy tenure, the
policy term in both the Niva Bupa Aspire plan and ICICI Lombard Max Protect plan is one, two and
three years.  Now let's talk
about some of the great benefits of these plans.
Friends, you get the great benefit of Lock Forever
in the Niva Bupa Aspire plan,
which is triggered after the
first claim. It is unlimited. Each claim
base will always be up to Rs. 1000, which can be used by the same person
on the same loan.
To understand this benefit in detail, you can comment
or call or message me on the number given on the screen.
In the ICICI Loard Max product plan, you have the
benefit of unlimited resets, in which you get the
benefit of unlimited claims up to the sum
assured. This benefit will not be applicable on unlimited sum assured.
Friends,
in the Aspire plan, you get the great benefit of Lock the Clock.
Your premium gets locked when you take the policy and it
remains locked until you make a claim. The
Lock the Clock feature is
available to you in the Niva Bupa Aspire Gold Plus variant.
Now the second benefit is Lock the Clock
Plus. Now this Lock the Clock feature is available in the Niva Bupa Aspire Gold Plus variant.  What is Lock the Clock Plus? Lock
the Clock Plus means Miracle
Benefit. Now what is Miracle Benefit?
Miracle Benefit is basically
related to maternity. So what will be one more thing added to Lock the Clock Plus? Firstly,
your premium will not increase as per your age until you
take a claim. Secondly, if you
take a maternity claim, there will be no break in it.
Your log age will continue.
Your premium will not be revised age
by age. Just to remind you,
if you have not yet subscribed to our channel, then
subscribe and
like our videos. If you have any questions related to this plan, then
ask us in the comments. Now let's talk about
Niva Vape Spire Bur Plus benefit.
Bur Plus is given to you in all four variants in different ways.
Bur Plus is the sum
insurance that you are not using will be carried
forward. So, in each variant,
your subscription can be carried forward as per your age.
To understand this benefit in detail, you can see me on the screen.  You
can call or message on the given number.
In the ICICI Lord Max Protect plan, you
get a guaranteed cumulative bonus of 20%,
maximum up to 100% and this bonus will
not be reduced on claim. Now let's
know about the health checkup benefit.
In the NB Spy plan,
you get free health checkups up to Rs 10,000 from
day one, which you
can avail on a cashless basis. In the ICICI Lord Max
Protect plan, you get free
annual health checkups up to Rs 10,000 only in the premium variant,
once during the policy period. Now let's talk about the features
that are covered in both the plans.
Features like inpatient treatment, domicile treatment, all-day care treatment, organ donor, AYUSH treatment are covered
in both the plans. The facility of up to the same
second medical opinion
is available to you for unlimited times.
Second medical opinion
for critical illness is available in the Niva Bopa Pay plan.
In the Protect plan,
pre- and post-hospitalization is
covered in both plans, where
pre-hospitalization is covered for 60 days and
post-hospitalization
is covered for up to 180 days in both plans. There is
no limit on room rent in the Niva B Span plan,
whereas in the ICICI Loard Max Protect
plan, you can choose any room except the
suite category. You will actually be charged.
Now, talking about the hospital cash
benefit, you get it only
in the Niva B Aspire plan. Up to 1,000 per day
as an optional rider is available to you.
Room type modification is available in the Niva B Aspire plan
with an additional
copayment of up to 25. Now, the best part
here is that in the Kiwa B Span plan,
you can claim from this policy even if you are admitted to the hospital for two hours or more.
Apart from this,
you can avail the benefit of unlimited e-consultation in both the plans.
This allows you to
consult a general physician. If you
ever undergo an organ transplant, Niva
Bupa will pay for the donor's hospitalization expenses for organ harvesting,
only if you are hospitalized.
If you donate any of your organs,
Niva Bupa will
also pay for the organ harvesting expenses.
Organ donor expenses are covered in the ICICI Lumbard Max Protect plan
up to the sum assured. Just to remind you,
if you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, please
subscribe
and like the video.
If you have any questions related to this plan, please
ask us in the comments.
Domiciliary hospitalization is covered in the Niva Bupa Aspire plan up to the sum assured. Domiciliary hospitalization is
covered in the ICICI
Lumbard Max Protect plan up
to Rs 1 lakh.
Road ambulance charges are also covered in both plans up to the sum assured in the Niva Bupa Aspire plan and a maximum of Rs 10,000 in the ICICI Lumbard Max Protect plan. Air ambulance charges are
covered in both plans up to the sum assured in the
Niva Bupa Aspire plan and a maximum of Rs
10,000 in the ICICI Lumbard Max
Protect plan.
In these plans, you will get cover up to the sum in short. There is an
optional benefit of aggregate deductible
which you get in the Niva Bupa Spire plan.
In the small deductible optional rider, you can reduce the premium of your policy.
What does deducted mean? If
you select a deductible of 1 lakh, then
if your bill comes up to 1 lakh, then you will pay it yourself, the
bill above that will be paid by the
company. Deduct tables are
available to you in this plan.
Now modern treatments or
advanced technology methods of 20000, 300, 50000 and up to ₹1 lakh are also
covered in both the plans. Up to the
sum in short. Now let us know about those optional
riders which are
available to you only in the Niva Bupa Aspire plan. The
first one is Fast Forward. If you are
paying the money for a multi-year policy together, then you can use both the
multi-year bed
sum, Inshot plus Miracle sum in short together under this optional rider.
You can avail the
maternity cover in the treatment.  If you want to increase your
coverage quickly, therefore, if you
take a multi-tenure policy together, then
your sum assured will also increase to 3x. That is, if
you have taken a policy of 20 lakhs and have
also taken the Miracle Benefit, then if you have taken a policy of 20 lakhs
for 3 years, then what will happen if
20 lakhs * 3, then you become eligible for 3x sum in short,
60 lakhs sum in short,
which you can use anytime, in 3 years.
Similarly, your Miracle Sum in Short will also increase to
3x. And in this, your deliveries are covered from day one,
so
you can take Fast Power Rider by paying an additional premium. The
second one is Future Ready. So
what does Future Ready mean? Future Ready means that
you have served all the waiting periods,
now your partner will not have to do that
during pregnancy and at the same time, your partner will get a
guarantee of pregnancy. With the help of Future Ready Rider,
you are taking guarantee
of your future spouse in this policy. When you
add your future spouse in this policy, then
your spouse will
not have to serve the waiting period.  For example, if the
maternity waiting period in your policy
is 24 months and you have
added your spouse to this policy after 2 years, then
your spouse will not have to go through the maternity waiting period,
their maternity will be
covered from day one itself. Third is borderless,
it means worldwide coverage, whether it is a
planned hospitalization or an emergency, then
worldwide coverage will be useful to you anywhere.
If you travel a lot, then
definitely opt for this rider as an optional rider in the policy. With the
help of this rider,
you can get treatment anywhere outside India, in
which your deductible will be applicable from
0% to up to 50%.
Fourth is cashback, so what is cashback basically? It is
not instant gratuity. When you
renew the policy, you get a cashback of 10% in the first year.
On paying the premium, you get a cashback of 5% in the second year. So, it keeps getting
added,
it keeps getting done. You will see your
Niva Bappa app in your wallet, which you use.  You
can pay the accumulative amount using points. Second, you
can claim OPD benefits from this cashback.
Third, if there is a co-pay event, you can pay that too.
Fourth, if you have
chosen a deductible, you can pay that through cashback.
Now, fifth is Well Consult. Let's
find out what is covered in this.
First, it includes online consultation,
along with offline consultation. If
you want to see a doctor
in their network hospital,
you will get cashless coverage. If you are
in a non-network hospital, that too is
covered on a remuneration basis,
but blood
tests are also included with a copayment of 20%. Gym
membership is also included. Now let's talk
about the Miracle Benefit, which is
available only in the Niva Bupa Spire plan.
Miracle Benefit is basically a maternity
benefit. What is covered in maternity?
Your delivery expenses are covered. The
birth expenses are
covered in it, Cesarean and normal
deliveries will be covered. The expenses of the newborn baby are covered.
Whatever expenses of the newborn baby are covered
up to the sum assured. Now the
limit of delivery expenses is
according to your sum assured. That is, if
you have taken a sum assured of Rs. 3 lakhs, then
you will get Rs. 000 for delivery expenses. If you have
taken a sum assured of Rs. 10 lakhs, then you will get
Rs. 20 to 25 lakhs, then you will
get Rs. 0000. And if the sum assured is Rs. 50 lakhs or Rs. 1 crore, then you will get
Rs. 2500000.
Apart from this, the antenatal expenses of the mother are also covered in Miracle Benefits, that is,
whatever expenses you incur, with regards
to doctor consultation, mother
vaccination, surrogacy, all this is covered
in this plan.  Adoption will also be
covered in this plan. If
you want to adopt a child, that too will be covered.
Apart from this, IVF is also
covered in this plan. Now your Miracle Ami
Shot will also be carried forward up
to the Booster Plus limits. If you
liked this benefit, then comment or like.
Apart from this, in Liv Healthy, you can avail
discount of up to 30% on the renewal premium.
Now let's talk about some benefits
which you get only in ICICI Lord
Max Protect Premium variant plan.
Worldwide cover is
available to you up to the sum assured maximum of up to 3 crores. Claim
protector is available in this plan in
which your non-payable items are included in this plan.
Preventive health
check up to 10,000 will be made available to you.
Emergency air ambulance is also covered up to the sum
assured. Option to change the room
category is available to you in this plan
only. In the Classic variant, if you  If you
want to change your category from any
category to single private room, then you
can do that here, which reduces your premium. There
is a payment to the zone
in ICICI Lord Max Protect plan. If you get
treatment from a lower zone to a higher zone, then
you will have to make a payment.
In ICICI Lombard Max Protect plan,
you are covered for bariatric surgery up to
the same time. Now let us know
about the waiting period of both the plans. There is an
initial waiting period of 30 days
in both the plans and in both the plans,
you will have a waiting period of 2 years
for specific diseases and a waiting period of 36 months
in the Pre-Egistify plan. Reduction in
pre-assisting disease and maternity
benefit waiting period is also
available in Niva Bupa Espay plan. In these multi-year
policies,
you will have a waiting period of 48 months in ICICI Lord Max Protect plan.
After opting for the optional rider by paying an additional premium in the policy till pre-egistify, Quick and
Hassle Free  Both companies have similar claim settlement procedures.
Now let's talk
about the stand-out features: A free look-
up period is available, allowing you to
cancel the policy within 15 days.
You also have the facility of lifelong renewability.
If you get your treatment done at a network hospital,
you
can avail cashless treatment. Alternative
treatments are also covered up to the sum assured.
Now let's talk about the bonus tip, which is the
Safeguard Plus benefit. If you select this optional
benefit in the Niva Bopa Spire plan, all
your non-
consumer sum assured will be covered. The second benefit that
you get in the Safeguard Plus option
is the Booster Benefit, which does
not impact your Booster Benefit if your
claim is up to Rs 1 lakh in a policy year. The
third benefit is the Sum Assured Safeguard,
which increases
your sum assured
every year based on the Consumer Price Index. To understand these benefits in detail,
you can comment or
call or message me on the number given on the screen.  You can There is
no third party administrator in both the companies
You get the facility of direct in-house claim settlement There is
cashless claim processing of 30 minutes
This company has a faster and hassle free claim
process In this company,
you can avail cashless treatment in the network hospitals of both the companies
and in case of
treatment in non-network hospitals,
you are given the facility of reimbursement claim in this policy
Here you get 24*7
customer service support and
you also get tax benefits on premium payment
Under section 80D,
you can see the premium and zone details of this plan on your screen
[Music]
Friends, this was a little information
about the comparison of Niva Bappa Spire and ICI Lombard Max Protect Plan.
So friends, that's all in today's video.
I have tried to cover it in a lot of detail in this video. I
hope
you found the information given in this video really useful.
We will keep bringing important information related to health and life insurance for you. All
those who are connected with us,
you can keep doing the same  Stay with us in this successful
and if you are new to our channel then
please subscribe to our channel and
become a part of our Thank you very much for staying with me till the end of this video